Now we're going to be talking about contraindications for hot stone massage.
As in any other body work, there are contraindications.
And for hot stone, here is as follows.
Anyone with high blood pressure, taking any medication that might react with heat, open wounds or sores, inflamed skin conditions, diabetes and neuropathy, which is numbness and tingling of the peripherals.
Also contraindicated is pregnancy.
During pregnancy, a hormone called relaxin is increased which lengthens and softens the tissue of the body and prepares it for birth.
The increased heat from the stones and the deep tissue work can further lengthen these tissues making it problematic for after birth when the tissues are trying to shorten.
As a therapist, you should be very thorough in your intake process.
Learn as much as you can about the client's health history.
And telling you this is helping us educate people about hot stone.
And anyone that's trying to get hot stone should know that some conditions are contraindicated.
Next we'll be talking about the benefits of hot stone.